so r 80 uses a technique called striping
to improve performance so if we have one
disc it will have a track 0 track one
track 2 etc and the problem is that
while the head is positioned to retrack
0 it cannot be reading track 1 and also
it's very far away from all of these
other tracks so what happens is really
we have to serialize accesses to all of
the tracks if we need to retracts 0 17
and 27 we will have to decide in what
order we access them but for each of
these accesses we move the CAD we read
the track we move on to something else
so we cannot get more performance than
just reading one track at a time at the
current rotational speed of the disc
what raid 0 does is it takes two disks
and makes them look like this one disk
by putting the original tracks 0 here
track 1 here track to here track 3 here
and so on so the idea is that now each
of these tracks is called a stripe now
and we're gonna put stripes 0 really
here stripe one here and so on so track
0 of the first disc gets track 0 from
the overall large disk track 0 here
however gets the stripe 0 so instead of
calling these tracks we call them
stripes to avoid confusion between
what's a track on a physical disk and
these things that really are tracks that
would belong to a fake disk that we
don't really have because really these
two disks are pretending to be this one
disk as far as performance is concerned
we get twice the data throughput if we
have two disks why well because well the
first disc is reading some data the
second could be reading data to and
because controllers and buses today are
faster than what the disk can get to
effectively we can transfer twice the
amount of data assuming that those discs
are actually transferring the data you
can be unlucky and all the data you want
is on the stripes that are placed on
this desk in which case you're going to
get only the data throughput of a single
disk but on average we tend to get
almost
twice the throughput of a single disc by
splitting the data across two disks like
this as far as latency is concerned
because we have more throughput we get
less queuing delay normally we will be
able to handle requests one at a time
here now we can actually in parallel do
two requests so in the queue we get
faster to the request by basically
handling previous requests faster but
what about reliability unfortunately it
gets worse than one disk